Permanent: 471 Laureles Grade Rd Carmel Valley, CA 93924

http://joekochevar.com joseph.kochevar@students.olin.edu | 831.236.1335

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Graduating Mechanical Engineering Student with a strong background in mechanical design, finite element analysis, fabrication, and optimization. Possesses multidisciplinary industry-level engineering experience and a demonstrated ability to perform in a multitude of roles with high levels of success.

EDUCATION

OLIN COLLEGE

BS IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Expected May 2016 | Needham, MA

Recipient of 4-year, 50% Olin Merit Scholarship Conc. in Entrepreneurship Senior - Cum. GPA: 3.68 / 4.0

COURSEWORK

ENGINEERING

Principles of Engineering†
Mechanical Design
Thermodynamics
Microfluidics
Mechanical and Aerospace Systems
Design For Manufacturing

ENTREPRENEURSHIP

The Entrepreneurial Initiative New Technology Ventures Intellectual Property and Patent Law (†: Returned as Course Assistant)

PATENTS

Remotely Tunable CVT* (*: Patent Pending)

SKILLS

FABRICATION

Mill • Lathe • CNC • Laser Cutter Waterjet • 3d Printing • Vinyl Cutter Pneumatic Tools • Tube Bending

SOFTWARE

SolidWorks • SolidWorks PDM AutoDesk Inventor • AutoCAD MATLAB • COMSOL • Arduino Java • C • C++ • HTML • Python

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR CAPSTONE: BOEING | MECHANICAL ENGINEER

Sept 2015 - Present | Needham, MA

- Optimizing 737 final manufacturing to improve cargo bay panel installation.
- Also acting as business manager, organizing budgeting and purchases.

OLIN COLLEGE BLIND SAILING | MECHANICAL ENGINEER

June 2015 - Aug 2015 | Needham, MA

• Led mechanical design to outfit a sailboat with equipment to enable it to be sailed competitively by blind sailors.

PROTEDYNE CORPORATION | MECHANICAL ENGINEERING INTERN June 2014 - Aug 2014 | Windsor, CT

- Assisted in design and modification of large-scale laboratory automation systems.
- Manipulated and created drawings, parts, and assemblies using SolidWorks.

INTUIT: QUICKBASE | PD Engineering Intern, Private Contractor June 2013 – March 2014 | Waltham, MA

- Worked as a full-time engineer on the QuickBase Delight Product engineering team.
- Answered customer feedback, and added features to the automated email system.

ATK AEROSPACE SYSTEMS | Engineering Intern

June 2012 - Aug 2012 | Monterey, CA

• Worked with a team of engineers on UAV sensing payload modules and advanced signal processing.

LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

OLIN BAJA SAE | TEAM CAPTAIN – DESIGN LEAD Aug 2012 – Present | Needham, MA

- Directed component- and system-level designs for four separate off-road racing vehicles
- All designs used CAD modeling in SolidWorks, and finite element analysis to meet FS standards.

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING PROJECTS

CVT DESIGN AND PATENT Sept 2015 - Present

• Currently patenting a remotely tunable Continuously Variable Transmission for off-road vehicles.

ORNITHOPTER Jan 2014 - May 2015

• Worked with two mechanical engineers to design, build, and test a miniature flapping-wing flying mechanism.

JARAH: OLIN COWORKER ROBOT Jan 2014 - May 2015

• Designed the chassis system for an interactive coworker robot for possible later production.

ROBOTIC GUITAR Oct 2013 - May 2015

• Acted as the mechanical lead in the design and construction of a self-playing guitar system.

CVT TESTING AND TUNING PLATFORM Oct 2012 - Present

- Designed and built platform to simulate, test, and tune Continuously Variable Transmissions.
- Made Olin Baja one of the first and only SAE Baja teams to have a full CVT simulation, testing, and diagnostic tool suite.